<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

   <statements version="1.0" htmlParse="false">
     <statement id="1">Being able to speak more than one language is an important part of my identity. 会说一种以上的语言是我身份认同中重要的一部分。</statement>
     <statement id="2">I am a multilingual person. 我认为自己是一个多语者。</statement>
     <statement id="3">Sometimes I feel like a different person when I speak in another language. 当我说另一种语言时，有时我感觉自己变成了另一个人。</statement>
     <statement id="4">I feel like I can show a different side of my personality when I speak in another language. 用另一种语言说话时，我感觉能展现性格中不同的一面。</statement>
     <statement id="5">Learning English has changed my personality. 学习英语改变了我的性格。</statement>
     <statement id="6">Learning Russian has changed my personality. 学习俄语改变了我的性格。</statement>
     <statement id="7">I feel connected and familiar when I hear people speak in a foreign language I know. 当我听到熟悉的外语时，会感到亲切。</statement>
     <statement id="8">Being able to speak English is an important part of my identity. 会说英语是我身份认同中重要的一部分。</statement>
     <statement id="9">Being able to speak Russian is an important part of my identity. 会说俄语是我身份认同中重要的一部分。</statement>
     <statement id="10">I think that I can express ideas in Russian that I can’t in L1 or L2. 我觉得在俄语中能表达一些在母语或英语中无法表达的想法。</statement>
     <statement id="11">I identify with the values and lifestyles of people from English-speaking countries. 我认同英语国家的价值观和生活方式。</statement>
     <statement id="12">I identify with the values and lifestyles of people from Russian-speaking countries. 我认同俄语国家的价值观和生活方式。</statement>
     <statement id="13">I would like to study Russian even if it was not required by the curriculum. 即使选课不要求，我也愿意学习俄语。</statement>
     <statement id="14">Being able to speak English makes me feel more confident and unique among my peers. 会说英语让我在同龄人中更自信、更独特。</statement>
     <statement id="15">Being able to speak Russian makes me feel more confident and unique among my peers. 会说俄语让我在同龄人中更自信、更独特。</statement>
     <statement id="16">I study foreign languages because I want to communicate with people from all over the world. 我学习外语，是因为我希望能与来自不同国家的人交流。</statement>
     <statement id="17">I believe that I will be a fluent speaker of Russian in the future. 我相信将来我会说一口流利的俄语。</statement>
     <statement id="18">I believe that I will be a fluent speaker of English in the future. 我相信将来我会说一口流利的英语。</statement>
     <statement id="19">Speaking several foreign languages will always be an important part of my identity even after I graduate. 毕业后，会说几种外语也会一直是我身份的重要部分。</statement>
     <statement id="20">I study Russian because I want to be a multilingual person rather than I love the language per se. 我学习俄语是因为我想成为一个多语者，而不是单纯喜欢这门语言。</statement>
     <statement id="21">My goal is to be able to speak English like a native speaker. 我的目标是说英语时像母语者一样自然。</statement>
     <statement id="22">My goal is to be able to speak Russian like a native speaker. 我的目标是说俄语时像母语者一样自然。</statement>
     <statement id="23">I study foreign languages in response to national initiatives, believing they will create new opportunities for my future. 我学习外语是为了响应国家倡议，并且相信这些倡议将为我的未来创造新的机遇。</statement>
     <statement id="24">Speakers of foreign languages will help me to get a better job. 我学习英语是因为英语有助于我将来找工作。</statement>
     <statement id="25">I think it’s hard to see when I will use Russian in the future. 我很难想象未来会在什么情境中使用俄语。</statement>
     <statement id="26">English is important for my future education. 英语对我未来的学业发展很重要。</statement>
     <statement id="27">Russian is important for my future education. 俄语对我未来的学业发展很重要。</statement>
     <statement id="28">I learn Russian mainly for pleasure rather than practicality. 我学习俄语主要是因为喜欢，而不是出于实用目的。</statement>
     <statement id="29">I study English because English will help me to get a better job. 我学习英语是因为英语有助于我将来找工作。</statement>
     <statement id="30">I find learning English enjoyable. 我觉得学英语很有趣。</statement>
     <statement id="31">I find learning Russian enjoyable. 我觉得学俄语很有趣。</statement>
     <statement id="32">I’m proud to be able to speak more than one language. 我为自己能说多种语言而感到自豪。</statement>
     <statement id="33">In China, fluency in several foreign languages will give me a competitive edge over people who can only speak English and their mother tongue. 在中国，掌握多门外语能让我比只会母语和英语的人更有竞争力。</statement>
     <statement id="34">For me, foreign languages skills are tools to achieve important goals. 对我来说，外语技能是实现重要目标的工具。</statement>
     <statement id="35">I am interested in foreign cultures in general. 我对外国文化普遍感兴趣。</statement>
     <statement id="36">I am interested in the culture(s) of English-speaking countries. 我对英语国家的文化感兴趣。</statement>
     <statement id="37">I am interested in the culture(s) of Russian-speaking countries. 我对俄语国家的文化感兴趣。</statement>
     <statement id="38">For me, studying other subjects (such as law, journalism, or economics) contributes more to my personal development than learning languages does. 对我来说，学法律、新闻或经济等其他学科比学语言对我的发展更有意义。</statement>
     <statement id="39">For me, language learning is simply a required part of my university curriculum. 对我来说，语言学习只是大学课程的一部分。</statement>
     <statement id="40">I prioritise learning English over Russian in my language learning. 在语言学习中，我更重视英语而非俄语。</statement>
     <statement id="41">With AI and translation apps, it’s hard to see the point of learning foreign languages. 现在有了AI和翻译软件，我觉得学习外语的必要性降低了。</statement>
     <statement id="42">Speaking English is a part of my everyday life. 英语是我日常生活的一部分。</statement>
     <statement id="43">Speaking Russian is a part of my everyday life. 俄语是我日常生活的一部分。</statement>
     <statement id="44">I have used Russian to communicate with people in real-life situations (e.g., exchange studies, traveling, online, talking to native speakers). 我曾用俄语在真实情境中与他人交流（如交换学习、旅行、上网、与母语者交流）。</statement>
     <statement id="45">My experience in learning English is making my Russian learning easier. 我的英语学习经验对俄语学习有帮助。</statement>
     <statement id="46">I can find role models for foreign language learning in my surroundings or online (e.g., teachers, classmates, influencers, translators, public figures). 我能在身边或互联网上找到语言学习的榜样（如老师、同学、网红、译员、公众人物等）。</statement>
     <statement id="47">I think other countries are less safe than China, which makes me feel worried about going abroad. 我觉得其他国家没有中国安全，这让我对出国有些担心。</statement>
     <statement id="48">I think English is often given more importance than other foreign languages in China. 我认为在中国，英语常比其他外语更受重视。</statement>
     <statement id="49">My Russian teachers have made me feel that learning Russian is meaningful and worth the effort. 我的俄语老师让我觉得学习俄语很有意义、值得付出努力。</statement>
     <statement id="50">I learn Russian because my family expects me to. 我学习俄语是因为家人希望我这样做。</statement>
     <statement id="51">I feel pressured to study Russian well, because I think people around me will be disappointed if I didn’t. 我觉得自己有压力要学好俄语，因为我担心如果没学好，身边的人会感到失望。</statement>
     <statement id="52">I study hard in foreign languages because this is what a student in relevant majors should do. 我努力学外语，是因为这就是外语专业学生该做的事。</statement>
     <statement id="53">Speaking English makes me nervous. 说英语时我会紧张。</statement>
     <statement id="54">Speaking Russian makes me nervous. 说俄语时我会紧张。</statement>
     <statement id="55">Some languages are more important to learn than others. 有些语言比其他语言更值得学习。</statement>
     <statement id="56">I like Russian better than English. 比起英语，我更喜欢俄语。</statement>
     <statement id="57">I don’t enjoy learning foreign languages yet I still want to learn them well because FL skills are useful for my future. 虽然我不喜欢学外语，但我仍希望学好它们，因为它们对我的未来很有帮助。</statement>
     <statement id="58">I like learning languages in general not only English and Russian. 我喜欢学语言，不只是英语和俄语。</statement>
     <statement id="59">I believe that have a talent in language learning in general. 我相信自己具备语言学习的天赋。</statement>
     <statement id="60">I would like to study English even if it was not required by the curriculum. 即使选课不要求，我也愿意学习英语。</statement>
     <statement id="61">I believe that I have a talent for learning Russian. 我相信自己在俄语学习方面有天赋。</statement>
     <statement id="62">Some languages are more important to learn than others. 有些语言比其他语言更值得学习。</statement>
   </statements>